# Adam Jelley PhD Candidate in Deep Reinforcement Learning

Email: adam.jelley@ed.ac.uk LinkedIn:linkedin.com/in/AdamJelley

GitHub: github.com/AdamJelley

#### **PROFILE**

PhD candidate in machine learning, with a background in theoretical physics and 3+ years experience of data science in industry. Research focused on developing reinforcement learning approaches to improve training efficiency, often using a multi-stage approach to avoid the cold-start problem. Interested in improving the scientific understanding of deep learning and reinforcement learning, bridging the gap between academia and industry, and the application of reinforcement learning to real-world problems and production software.

#### **EDUCATION**

# PhD in Efficient Deep Reinforcement Learning, University of Edinburgh May 2021 - Current

- PhD research aimed at developing more sample/compute efficient deep reinforcement learning.
- Supported by a Microsoft Research PhD Scholarship.
- Supervised by Professor Amos Storkey and Dr Sam Devlin (Microsoft Research).

# Centre for Doctoral Training in Data Intensive Science, UCL

Sept 2018 - March 2019

• Initial research training included courses on Research Software Engineering (in Python), Statistics and Data Analysis, and Machine Learning with Big Data.

Natural Sciences – Physics (MSci, BA), University of Cambridge October 2012 – June 2016

- MSci Phys: 1st Class, 84% average Ranking 2nd in Cambridge MSci Physics
  - o Specialised in Quantum Field Theory
  - o Dissertation on "Invisibility and Maxwell's Equations"
  - o Won BP Nevill Mott Prize for the Best Masters Theoretical Physics Research Project
- BA Phys: 1st Class, 80% average
  - o Won Queens' College Chalmers Prize for Physics

#### Sir Thomas Rich's Grammar School, Gloucester

2005 - 2012

**A Levels:** 4 at A\*

**AS Levels:** 5 at A

**GCSEs:** 10 at A\*

# SELECTED PUBLICATIONS (See Google Scholar for full list)

"Diffusion for World Modeling: Visual Details Matter in Atari" (NeurIPS 2024 Spotlight)
E Alonso\*, A Jelley\*, V Micheli, A Kanervisto, A Storkey, T Pearce\*, F Fleuret\* (\* for equal contribution)

"Aligning Agents like LLMs" (RLC Workshop on Reinforcement Learning Beyond Rewards 2024)
A Jelley, Y Cao, D Bignell, S Devlin, T Rashid

"Efficient Offline Reinforcement Learning: The Critic is Critical" (ICML Workshop on Aligning Reinforcement Learning Experimentalists and Theorists 2024) A Jelley, T McInroe, S Devlin, A Storkey

"Contrastive Meta-Learning for Partially Observable Few-Shot Learning" (ICLR 2023)

A Jelley, A Storkey, A Antoniou, S Devlin

#### **INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE**

# Research Scientist Intern – Microsoft Research, Cambridge June 2023 – September 2023

• Developed a pipeline for aligning agents with preferences on the Xbox game Bleeding Edge using Reinforcement Learning from Human Feedback (RLHF), for research on capabilities and limitations.

# Lead Data Scientist - Dataiku, London

July 2020 - April 2021

- Led the UK and Northern Europe region's data science team to prioritise, scope and deliver client-facing and internal data science projects.
- Managed and coached a team of 6 data scientists, including hiring, progression and project allocation.

# Data Scientist - Dataiku, London

April 2019 – July 2020

- Delivered both client-facing and internal data science projects, including time-series forecasting of
  vaccination production, automated PDF processing, novel material patent classification, medical image
  analysis and marketing recommendation engines among others.
- Employed a range of machine learning tools and techniques to develop and deploy data science solutions
  into production, utilising Python (Scikit-learn, Keras, TensorFlow, Pandas, NumPy), SQL and Dataiku's
  Data Science Studio with various underlying architectures for both batch and real-time use cases.
- Presented at conferences including Big Data London and the AI in Retail Summit Europe.

# Consultant - Applied Predictive Technologies, London August 2016 - October 2017

- Utilised predictive analytics and SQL to analyse large datasets (including the global Mastercard transaction log) to calculate the performance of business trials and to build models to predict their wider impact.
- Presented recommendations to key stakeholders up to and including C-level across a range of businesses.

# **CONFERENCE PRESENTATIONS**

Improving Recommender Systems with Deep Learning

AI in Retail and Advertising Summit, 2019

Machine Learning in Real-Time: Predicting Taxi Fares in NYC

Big Data London, 2019

Sort It: Build a PDF Processor

Bright TALK (Online Webinar), 2020

# **TEACHING EXPERIENCE**

Teaching Assistant Reinforcement Learning University of Edinburgh, 2021-2024

Tutor / Marker Machine Learning and Pattern Recognition University of Edinburgh, 2021-2023

#### **TECH STACK**

Proficient: Python, including PyTorch, Scikit-learn, Pandas, Numpy; SQL; LinuxFamiliar: Cloud (GCP, Azure), Docker, Kubernetes, Spark, Javascript, CSS, HTML